Alchemy is a science where one understands the structure of matter, breaks it down, then rebuilds it.
However, it is not an all-powerful technique,
as one cannot create something out of nothing.
If one wishes to gain something,
one must present something of equal value.
This is the concept of equivalent exchange, the fundamental basis of alchemy.
However, there is a taboo in alchemy. Human transmutation.
One must not commit this act.
I've still got a lot of years ahead of me
Kono omoi wo keshiteshimau niwa
To just erase these feelings?
Mada jinsei nagai desho?
I want to go back and finish
Yarinokoshiteru koto
The things that I've yet to finish.
Yarinaoshite mitai kara
I was supposed to be chasing after my ongoing dream,
Yume no tsuzuki oikaketeita hazu nanoni
Yet I faltered over others while walking this thin, winding path.
Magarikunetta hosoi michi hito ni tsumazuku
It's not that I want to return to those days.
Ano koro mitainitte modoritai wake ja nai no
I'm searching for the sky I lost.
Nakushitekita sora wo sagashiteru
Don't make that sad face, as if you've fallen victim.
Wakatte kuremasu youni
As if you want people to pity you.
Gisei ni natta youna kanashii kao wa yameteyo
Tears aren't the end of your sins.
Tsumi no saigo wa namida ja nai yo
You have to bear them painfully, forever.
Zutto kurushiku seottekunda
Who are you waiting for in the maze of emotions,
Deguchi mienai kanjoumeiro ni
Where you can't even see the exit?
Dare wo matteruno?
I want to blurt it out more justly,
Shiroi nooto ni tsuzutta youni
Just like how I wrote it in my white notebook.
Motto sunao ni hakidashitai yo
What do you want to run from?
Nani kara nogaretainda
That thing called "reality"?
Genjitsu tte yatsu?
I just want to scream out,
Kanaeru tame ni ikiterundatte
"I'm only living to fulfill my wish." Can you hear me?
Sakebitaku naru yo kikoeteimasuka?
I can't take the safe way out of everything.
Bunan ni nante yatterarenaikara
I don't even have a place to return to.
Kaeru basho mo nai no
I'm always thankful for everyone's kindness,
Yasashisa ni wa itsumo kansha shiteru
That's why I want to become stronger. (I'm on the way)
Dakara tsuyoku naritai (I'm on the way)
This is reminding me of the old days.
Natsukashiku naru
This pain is all right with me.
Konna itami mo kangei jan
Marcoh, the man who Ed and Al met, possessed
a Philosopher's Stone, although it was incomplete.
Moved by Ed's passion, Marcoh revealed the location his research data was hidden.
And so, after having his automail repaired,
Ed stood before the place Marcoh's data was located...
National Central Library, 1st Branch.
Dr. Marcoh's research data!!!
It was too much effort to look for it,
so I just burnt down the whole building.
What did you do at Central?
That's exactly what I've been explaining to you!
The Fullmetal boy found out about Marcoh's data.
After I took care of that, I came back to East City to check on things, but...
How's he doing?
Gluttony?
I can smell... I can smell it.
There's an Ishbalan nearby that smells like blood.
Can I eat him?
Sure, but eat every bit of him.
Hidden Truths
There have been no sightings of Scar
since the case involving the Elric brothers.
Maybe he's not in East City anymore?
I need him to be here.
Huh?
If I can solve the case that was left unresolved in Central, it should raise my status in the public's eye.
I'll take advantage of everything I can.
Until I become the Führer and gain full authority over the military, that is.
You ought to refrain from making inappropriate remarks.
Yeah, I'll try.
Excuse me, sir!
There has been a report of an explosion by Merle River!
What?!
A gas explosion?
No idea.
It's been so unsafe lately.
This belongs to Scar. There's no mistaking it.
Have any bodies been found?
We've been searching, but...
In any case, judging from this blood, it is safe to assume that he's dead.
But still, we cannot let our guard down until we confirm his death.
Second Lieutenant Havoc.
Sir?
Your squad is to clear all of the rubble.
There will be no breaks, whether it be for lunch or supper.
Drag his body out, no matter what it takes.
Give us a break.
Are you trying to kill us?
Shut up!
I can't even calm myself for a date until I see his dead body with my own eyes.
Yeah, okay.
He got away.
I didn't get to eat him...
There, there, maybe next time.
Well, he probably won't be able to do anything for a while after all that.
I'm going back to Central again.
I need to report to Father about Scar.
Everything's been burnt to a crisp.
Major Armstrong!
Ah, 2nd Lt. Ross and Sergeant Brosh.
What's the matter?
We've received orders from Headquarters to report.
We will take over the escort of Sir Edward Elric.
All right, understood.
What the heck?! Just when I thought I'd get rid of this smothering guy for good, I get more escorts?!
There is someone well-versed in the data that was in the Library's 1st Branch.
Although she is no longer employed...
Looks like I shouldn't expect much.
Can I help you?
U-Umm...
Pardon my impudence, but why are you wearing a suit of armor?
Just a hobby!
"Hobby"? Second Lieutenant, what kind of hobby is it?!
What's wrong with these kids?!
Man, Al, the scenery is great!
You're right, Brother!
Wha-
What's with these mountains of books?!
Is there really someone living here?
Miss Sheska, are you in?
Miss Sheska!
Someone...
Help me...
Huh?
Hm?
Brother, someone...
Someone is buried under the books!
Dig! Dig! Dig! Dig over here!
PLACEHOLDER
Idiot!!
Hang in there!
I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
I carelessly knocked over a mountain of books...
I thought that was the end for me!
Thank you so much!
So you're Sheska?
Yes.
The one who was at the 1st Branch?
1st Branch!
Ah, even the name gives off a sweet sound!
I've always loved books ever since I was born, and I felt like I was being sent to Heaven when I got a job there.
But I forgot that I was at work and was fired because I was reading all the time.
Even though I need a job to send
my sick mother to a better hospital...
Seriously... I've got no skills besides reading, and I can't find a job no matter where I go...
That's right! I'm a failure! I'm the trash of society!
Umm... I've got something I want to ask you...
Yes?
Do you happen to know of any
research documents by Tim Marcoh?
Tim Marcoh... Tim Marcoh...
Oh! Yes, I do remember!
Really?!
I remember it clearly because it was handwritten and shoved into a shelf in the wrong section.
So it really was there...
...which means that it's ashes now...
Did you want to read the research?
Yeah, but it's gone now...
Sorry to bother you.
I remember everything in it, though.
What?!
W-Well, I remember the content of every book that I've ever read.
It'll take a while, but would you like me to transcribe it?
Thank you so much, bookworm!
...Worm?
Here is the duplicate of Mr. Tim Marcoh's research!
Sorry, it took five days because there was just so much to write down.
There really are amazing people in this world, aren't there, Brother?
Is this really Dr. Marcoh's research?
Yes! No doubt about it!
"1000 Meals for Daily Living", written by Tim Marcoh.
Huh?
"Add a bit of water to a tablespoon of sugar"...
These really are 1000 meals for daily living.
Hey! What part this makes it an important document?!
But... all I did was copy things down exactly as I'd remembered!
Looks like we just went on a wild goose chase.
This is word for word what Dr. Marcoh wrote, right?
Yes! Without a doubt.
You're amazing. Thanks a lot.
Okay! Let's take this back to the Central Library.
Yeah. They've got a lot of related books there, too.
Yep.
Oops. I need to reward you for all that work.
2nd Lt. Ross, this is my registration code
and silver pocket watch as ID.
Withdraw the amount written on there from
my annual research expenditures and give it to Sheska.
Okay, so I just have to go to the state alchemist facility at the Führer administrative building, right?
Yep!
Thanks again, Sheska!
Later!
Hmm, so from his research expenditures...
What's with this number?!
He can just pull out a sum like this as if it's nothing?! What is that boy?!
Are these recipes really research documents for alchemy?
Alchemy is dangerous when abused.
To prevent that, alchemists encrypt their research.
An ordinary person may think it's just a cooking experiment; only the one who wrote it will understand the content.
Basically, it's an advanced alchemy document.
How are you going to decipher it
if only the author can understand it?
Knowledge and inspiration.
The rest of it will all be busy work with patience.
Wow, this'll take a while...
Al, there's something about a pigeon dish!
Pigeon? Could that be...
Yeah.
It could be about the Green Lion. The philosopher's moon.
Did you bring Flamel's manuscripts
or books on Lambspring's philosopher's stone?
Of course!
Great. Hey, look here.
Hmm?
This has to do with it, too, doesn't it?
Yeah, you're right! This one, too.
Yep. All right, let's give it a shot!
Why is this encryption hard as hell...
Don't you think it'll be faster to just ask Dr. Marcoh himself...
No! If we ask him, we lose!
Is that the problem here?
Umm...
Sheska.
I was able to transfer my mother to a wonderful hospital thanks to you.
I really appreciate it.
No problem at all.
Any progress on the decoding?
Have you found a job?
But thanks to you two, I realized that even a failure like me can be useful to others.
Thank you so much.
You're not a failure at all.
I believe being able to wholeheartedly commit yourself to something is a talent in itself,
and you have an amazing memory.
You should have more confidence in yourself.
Thanks.
Yo!
Lt. Colonel Hughes!
I heard from Major Armstrong you guys were back.
Come on... I told you guys to come
say hi when you stopped by Central again.
Sorry, I had urgent matters to take care of.
Yeah, I've been kind of busy too...
He's chatting to Lt. Colonel Hughes like they're buddies!
What are those boys?
There's been a lot of incidents and such lately.
The case with Tucker and the chimera hasn't been solved yet, either...
Oh... sorry.
I made you remember it.
Well, you know.
It's busy enough, and the 1st Branch of the library just had to burn down.
The 1st Branch?
Yeah. We kept a lot of case records and whatnot in the archives, so it really messes with our job.
Hm? What?
What do you think, Lt. Colonel?
This woman is looking for a job.
Yes, I have read army criminal records and remember them, but...
All right! Let's get you set up right away!
We pay really well!
That's... umm...
Thank you very much!
I'm going to have more confidence in myself, and I'll try my best.
Thank you so much!
Come on! I need you to get to work right away.
What is he, a kidnapper?
"I believe being able to wholeheartedly commit yourself to something is a talent in itself", huh...
Wise words, little bro.
I really feel that way, especially when I look at a certain someone.
Then that certain someone's going to keep working hard.
Oops.
Closing time.
It's been ten days already.
I can't believe they have the fortitude
to work every day until this place closes.
Bullshit!!!
Sibling fight?
You shouldn't get desperate simply because you can't solve it...
We did solve it.
We solved the code.
Seriously? That's great!
Hell no, it's not great!
"The Devil's research"...
"Something you mustn't desire"...
I resent you, Dr. Marcoh...
What... exactly...
The ingredients of philosopher's stones...
...are live humans.
And on top of that, you need several sacrifices just to refine one stone.
I would have never thought something so inhumane was going on in the army...
That's something that can't be forgiven.
Could you please not tell anyone about this?
But...
Please!
Forget about it.
What...
The Elric brothers have locked themselves in their room again today?
Yes. They haven't eaten much, either.
Perhaps they were really tired?
Seems they've been working extremely hard these past days, too.
I mean, if that's  what they found after all of that difficult deciphering...
Even I start feeling sick when I start thinking about it.
What is it?
N-Nothing!
Sounds fishy!
Brother, go get something to eat.
I'm not hungry.
This is tough.
Yeah.
It's like...
Right when you get within arm's reach, it runs away...
...and when you finally grab it, it kicks you down.
God must really hate humans who have committed taboo.
I wonder if we'll be like this for the rest of our lives...
Hey... there's something I've always wanted to ask you...
...but I've been too scared to.
What is it?
Elric brothers! You're there, aren't you?
It's me. Open up!
What should we do...
Just ignore him.
I heard the whole story, Edward Elric!
What a tragedy!
To think that such a horrifying secret laid beneath the philosopher's stone!
S... Sorry...
Not much we could do when such
a smothering person approaches you...
To think the army had been doing such a thing...
The truth can be cruel at times.
Truth...
What's wrong, Brother?
Do you remember Dr. Marcoh's words?
Huh?
"You may be able to reach
the real truth that is beyond truth..."
The real truth beyond truth...
Same as a research document for alchemy.
What can be seen from the outside is only a portion of the truth.
There's still something else!
Something...
There are currently four alchemy research laboratories owned by the government within Central.
The one Dr. Marcoh belonged to is Research Laboratory 3.
This one is the most suspicious.
We went around to every research lab in the city,
but this one wasn't particularly...
This. What's this building?
That would be Research Laboratory 5,
but it's not being used right now.
No one is allowed to enter it due to risk of collapse.
This is the place.
What makes you say that?
There's a prison right next to it.
And...
Do you remember what's needed to create philosopher's stones?
Umm... was it live humans...
There are bound to be people on the death row at the prison.
They tell the public they were executed, and...
Don't tell me... the prisoners are the ingredients?
Don't make that face.
I don't want to think about it, either.
The prison is under a different
jurisdiction, but if it's involved...
Does this mean the government has something to do with it?
I feel like I've stuck my nose into something horrible...
That's why we asked you to forget about it!
This may turn into a political matter.
I'll look into it.
But until then, the 2nd Lt. and
the Sergeant are not to speak of it!
Yes, sir!
You two better not do anything, either.
You two were thinking of sneaking into the building to check it out, weren't you!!
We weren't! We weren't!
We were.
A guard at an unused building, eh?
Pretty suspicious.
How should we get in?
How about we just make an entrance?
They'll notice the flash of the transmutation response.
In that case...
Here we... go!
This place is completely shut down, too.
Al, wait here.
Will you be all right on your own?
Either way, you can't get through here with that big body of yours, can you?
Not like I chose to have a big body!
66.
What, 48?
Our first guest in quite a while.
What a reckless dumbass.
This is narrower than I'd thought, dammit.
I probably wouldn't have been able to get through if I was normal-sized.
Good thing I'm small.
Crap! I called myself small!!!
The lights are on.
Not being used right now my ass.
Bingo.
Brother sure is taking his time...
Say, the sky we saw that day, the scarlet sky.
Ano hi mita sora akaneiro no sora wo
Do you remember it from that day?
Nee kimi wa oboeteimasuka
We made a promise and a vow while the early summer wind circled us.
Yakusoku chigiri shoka no kaze ga tsutsumu
And we clung close together.
Futari yorisotta
Your forced smile
Muri na egao no ura
Holds elongated shadows.
Nobita kage wo kakumau
I pretend not to notice and continue on.
Dakara kizukanu furi saisei wo erabu
All the while waiting for you to deliver some news at the table.
Teeburu no ue no furuenai shirase machitsuzukete
Empty nights, mornings that will never arrive,
Kuuhaku no yoru mo kuru hazu no nai asa mo
I could see them from a mile away.
Zenbu wakattetanda
Say, the sky we saw that day, the scarlet sky.
Ano hi mita sora akaneiro no sora wo
I'm sure you'll remember it one day.
Nee itsuka omoidasu deshou
While holding the promise we couldn't keep,
Hatasenakatta yakusoku wo idaite
We take our first steps down our own paths.
Futari arukidasu
There was a man who held pride in his swordsmanship,
and there was also another man who understood he was a heretic.
The residents of darkness jeer, and
the blades that drank blood are shrieking.
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
Episode 8, The Fifth Laboratory.
The Fifth Laboratory
Ones who seek pleasure in fighting and continue to live forever...
...speak thy names.